下午好  塞达维尔
Good afternoon, Cedarville!
很荣幸籍我之手
It is my distinct honor to present
将年度社区服务奖
our annual community service award
颁给我们最杰出的一位市民
to one of our most outstanding citizens.
台下不少人或知
Now, many of you may recognize him
他是我们冠军少棒队的教练鲍勃
as coach Bob of our champion little league team.
或许有人知道他是
And some of you may know him
嘉实奖学基金的司库
as the treasurer of our Harvest Scholarship Fund.
但我确信  你们都知道
But I know that all of you know him as the guy
他是全镇唯一一个加油站的拥有者
that owns the only gas station in town.
鲍勃·哈里斯  请上台
Bob Harris, get on up here
带上你美丽的家人
with that beautiful family of yours!
鲍勃·哈里斯  各位
Bob Harris, folks!
鲍勃  你积极服务社区
Bob, your community activism,
热衷公益
charity work,
是塞达维尔民众的典范
and character represent the finest Cedarville has to offer.
请代大家接受这个奖
Please accept this on behalf of all of us
要知道我们都爱你
and know that we love you.
你还好吧
Are you all right?
鲍勃
Bob?
你压得我透不过气
You're crushing me!
醒醒
Wake up!
我想你心脏病发了
I think you're having a heart attack.
我这就叫救护车
I'm gonna call the ambulance!
不  送我去医院就可以
No. Just drive me to the hospital.
总监：
zlean
作为新院长
As the new dean of medicine,
我想亲自欢迎新员工
I'd like to personally welcome all of our new employees
并且  我得问  你们为什么想回来
and ask, why the hell do you want to come back?
冲浪冲腻了
Tired of surfing.
他一点没变
He hasn't changed.
工作内容也没变  对吧
And neither has the job, right?
我们还是不择手段救死扶伤吧
We still get to do crazy crap?
救人性命而非只是整形开刀
Save people's lives instead of just their noses?
关于那个  不择手段救死扶伤
About that... about the crazy stuff?
开始了
Here we go.
他由同伴变成了敌人
He's gone from ally to enemy.
人家别无选择  人家现在是老板
He has no choice. He's the boss now.
人家得在其位  谋其事
He has to be professional.
人家每做一个决定
He has to base his decisions
都得从医院的利益出发
on what's best for the entire hospital.
这不是针对我们
We can't take it personally.
是不是我自己说更好一点
Couldn't have said it better myself.
你已经打好草稿
You did.
我只不过把你桌上的稿子念出来
I'm just reading the notes on your desk.
他还想让我们做他的眼线
He also wants us to spy for him.
不是眼线
Not spy.
我是不想豪斯进监狱
I'm trying to keep house out of prison.
出于那个目的  我需要知道他的所作所想
To do that, I need to know what he's doing and planning.
-眼线  -眼线
- Spy. - Spy.
我说  伙计们  我是你们老板
Come on, guys. I am your boss.
你们得有点分寸
You do have to treat me appropriately.
但也不必太过拘谨
But it doesn't have to be awkward and weird.
工作之外  我还把你们当朋友
Outside of work, I still consider us all friends.
很高兴你这么想
I'm glad you feel that way,
因为我确实有事相求
because I do have a favor to ask.
我告诉豪斯我下周才能回来
I told House I couldn't come back until next week.
他说他完全理解  接着叫我滚蛋
He said he understood completely and that I was fired.
所以
So...
因为我家孩子还得随我待两天
since I have my kids for the next two days,
我需要个保姆
I need a babysitter.
不行
No!
男性病人发生室颤
Male patient went into v-fib
但没有心脏疾病的迹象
but shows no signs of heart disease
也未出现任何其它症状
or any other symptoms, for that matter.
他的心脏闹别扭时
What was he doing
他在做什么
when his heart decided to do the mambo?
他说他在工作
He said he was at work.
你迟到了
You're late.
照我的日程表  我早了一星期
According to my calendar, I'm a week early.
胡子这招挺好使
Beard's a nice touch.
让大家知道你不是个大姑娘
Lets everyone know that you're not a teenage girl.
哦  你俩真登对
Oh, now, you two make a cute couple.
而你俩
And you two...
也罢
It's not important.
朴克医生
Dr. Park.
你比我想象中要高很多啊
You're a lot taller than I thought you'd be.
我也很期待与你合作
And I look forward to working with you as well.
他在说谎  不只陶博  还有病人
He's lying, not just Taub--the patient.
他膝盖的擦伤
These abrasions on his knees--
是新弄的
They're minty fresh...
大概就十小时前
about ten hours old.
他玩腰旗橄榄球时弄的
He got them playing flag football.
他说他玩腰旗橄榄球时弄的
He said he got them playing flag football.
我肯定"旗"指代阴茎
I'm sure that's true if "Flag" is a euphemism for "Penis"
玩橄榄球是"插入阴道"的委婉说法
and "Football" is a euphemism for "Entering a vagina."
他为什么要说谎
Why lie about it?
人人都说谎
Everybody lies.
话说
Speaking of which,
你的俩宝贝闺女呢
how are your two baby girls?
双胞胎  恭喜
Wow, twins-- congratulations.
囧
Awkward!
他同时搞大了两个女人的肚子
He knocked up two different women at the same time...
至少他这么认为
At least he thinks he did.
-你验DNA了吗  -为什么
- You have them DNA tested yet? - Why would I?
-他们长得像我  -小孩会长变样
- They look just like me. - But they will grow.
去查出他还隐瞒了什么
Find out what else he's lying about.
做个运动测试
Do an exercise test--
看能否让他再次室颤
See if you can get him to go back into v-fib again.
可致他再次心脏骤停
But we could end up causing another cardiac arrest.
希望如此  那样的话我们就能找出病因
Hopefully. Then we'll know what set it off.
他是说  在医院发病
He means it's better to do it here
总要好过在外面
where we can revive him
在这里我们能及时施救
than have it happen somewhere else.
浪子回头
The prodigal son has returned.
现在  恕我失陪
Now, if you'll excuse me,
我得去杀鸡宰羊筹备午宴[欢饮回来]
I have to go slaughter a fatted calf for lunch.
我告诉过你们  心脏病发时
I told you, I was sitting at my desk
我就坐在书桌旁
when the attack happened.
这些擦伤来自昨晚
These rug burns are from last night.
我们认为你当时在做爱
We think you were having sex,
但是失忆可能也是一个症状
but memory loss could also be a symptom.
也许我们该问问你老婆
Maybe we should ask your wife.
别
Don't.
我  我昨晚做了蠢事
I-I did something stupid last night,
不过那只是一夜情
but it was a one-time thing.
你们不知道我有多后悔
You have no idea how bad I feel about it.
你有负罪感  那是你们夫妻俩的事
Your guilt is between you and your wife.
我们只需知道当时发生了什么
We just need to know what happened.
我在汽车旅馆里正做爱
I was having sex at a motel
突然感觉有点眩晕
when I started to feel light-headed.
等我恢复神智时  我已面朝天花板躺着
Next thing I knew, I was laying on my back.
几乎不能呼吸
I could barely breathe.
情况怎么样
Is everything all right?
我们准备进行运动测试
We'd like to perform an exercise test,
增加其身体负荷  模拟发病时的状态
re-create the stress that may have caused his symptoms.
他当时坐在书桌旁
He was sitting at his desk.
我们担心他的心脏有问题
It's his heart we're worried about.
测试时将实时监测他的心律
The test will monitor its rhythm
这样我们就能发现任何的异常
so we can check for any abnormalities.
被关过一个月禁闭之后
I spent a month in solitary.
你是觉得敲一天门这事我干不出来吗
You don't think I can keep this up all day?
我头疼着呢  能不能麻烦你小点声
I have a headache. Could you just lower your voice?
奇斯和陶博回来喽
Chase and Taub are back!
要我买个冰激凌蛋糕庆祝吗
You want me to pick up an ice-cream cake?
我觉得陶博今天
I also think that Taub
带了他家两个小不点一起来上班了
has brought his little Taubettes into work with him today.
怎么会
Why would he do that?
我没给他足够的时间做出其它选择
Because I didn't give him time to do anything else.
于是我就开始琢磨
Then I started wondering,
会有哪个滥好人愿意帮他照顾小孩呢
who'd be sappy enough to watch them for him?
她们不在我这
They're not here.
说啥呢
What?
我就是来和老朋友聊聊天的
I just came for a chat with a friend.
朋友  这是什么味道
What's that I smell, friend?
你的疑惑我非常理解
I understand your confusion.
我午餐的时候吃了一个婴儿  再加上...
I was eating a baby for lunch,and...
我头痛越来越严重了
I have a massive migraine.
你能不能别在我面前晃了
Will you please just go away?
你应该躺下来  好好休息会
You should probably lie down and rest.
没错  我正有此意
Yeah. I was trying to.
不过  还有一件事
Oh! There is one more thing.
他的身体状态太好了
He's in too good of shape.
我们得让他达到昨天晚上的状态
We need to get him to the point he was at last night.
别指望我
Well, don't look at me.
但要是你愿意的话
But if you want to...
犀利
Cute.
不过我想说的不是身体上的压力
But I didn't mean physical stress.
难道你们男人就不明白什么叫不负责任吗
Don't you guys think this is irresponsible?
好比说你让两个女人同时怀了孩子
It's like you getting two women pregnant at the same time.
我只是想说这种事情发生的概率
I just mean the part about the odds of it happening.
应该高得不可思议吧
They had to be incredibly high.
如果真的出现室颤的话
And if we induce V-fib,
从概率上来说  我们应该能把他救回来
odds say that we'll be able to revive him.
但不怕一万就怕万一
But there's always a chance we can't.
又极端又鲁莽  这就是豪斯
It's extreme and reckless. That's House.
你得适应才行
You get used to it.
要么我就会炒了你
Or I fire you.
看看我的新发现
Look what I found...
两个小盆友
Kiddie-winkies!
不知道她们是谁家的
I wonder who they belong to.
我的孩子  给我
Give me my kids.
我说真的  我真心想知道她们是谁的娃
No. I genuinely wonder who they belong to.
我需要一个DNA样本
I need a DNA sample.
我是不会让你对我的孩子做DNA测试的
I'm not letting you DNA test my kids.
已经完成了  这支棉签是给你准备的
Already did. This swab's for you.
好吧  要是你这么不差钱
Fine. If you don't mind paying a fortune
愿意养别人家的小孩
in child support for some other guy's kids,
我瞎操什么心
no skin cells off my cheek.
心律终于上去了
His heart rate's finally elevating.
奇斯医生说你有话要和我说
Dr. Chase said you had something to tell me.
我们刚刚说到你膝盖上的擦伤是怎么回事
We were talking about how you got the abrasions on your knees
腰旗橄榄球的事
the flag football game.
对了  亲爱的  你得帮我向他们告个假了
Yeah, honey, I'm gonna need you to let the guys know
我周六应该去不了了
I'm not gonna be able to play on saturday.
整个镇上的人都知道你住院了
The whole town knows that you're in the hospital.
不用担心
I wouldn't worry about it.
你想说的不是这个吧
That's not what you wanted to tell her.
你不是说那次比赛不太寻常吗
You said the game wasn't typical.
发生了一些让你心烦的事
Something happened that you were upset about?
我不太懂  你说的是
I don't understand. What are you--
我感觉  感觉不太
I don't f-- I don't feel very w--
他怎么了
What's happening?
不是心脏问题
It's not his heart.
我知道
I know.
他癫痫发作了
He's having a seizure.
他癫痫发作时
There wasn't any abnormal electrical activity in his E.K.G.
心电图上显示一切正常
when his seizure occurred.
不是室颤引发的
It wasn't caused by a V-fib.
但也不能完全排除
We still can't rule it out.
从急救室那边的心电图结果来看
His E.K.G. from the E.R. documented--
心肌炎
Myocarditis--
病毒性感染导致心脏壁肌受损
Viral infection weakening the wall muscles.
我们要对他的心脏做活检确认
We need to biopsy his heart to confirm.
心肌炎不会引起癫痫
Myocarditis wouldn't cause a seizure.
可能是原发性疾病  布鲁格达氏综合症
Could be genetic-- Brugada Syndrome.
感谢上帝
Oh, my god.
又一个浪子回头啊
Two prodigal sons.
来来来  拥抱一下
Come on. Let's hug it out.
你是真觉得我想得不错呢
You really like the idea,
还是想从我这拔根头发做亲子鉴定
or you just want to grab some hair for a DNA test?
你的想法蠢到家了
It's a stupid idea.
真是那样  应该能从心电图上看出端倪来
We would have seen evidence of Brugada in the E.K.G.
这沙发
You know, this is...
根本就是在破坏我这的好风水
This is just messing with my Feng Shui here.
那里怎么样
What about over there?
嗜铬细胞瘤
A pheochromocytoma.
肾上腺素过量会导致心脏问题
Excess adrenaline can cause heart problems
以及癫痫
and...seizures.
没意思
Boring!
不好意思  我来这是为了救死扶伤
I'm sorry. I thought I was here to treat the patients,
不是逗你开心的
not entertain you.
你就不能一石二鸟吗
Would it hurt to do both?
这样果然好多了
Oh, this is much better!
我说没意思  又没说它错
I said it was boring. I didn't say it was wrong.
那你觉得我是对的
So I'm right.
不  你是错的  光源性癫痫
Nope. You're wrong. Photic epilepsy--
同样无趣
It's equally boring,
不过这个倒有可能是对的
But it has the advantage of possibly being right.
做个脑电图看看
Give him an E.E.G. to confirm.
要是你什么时候听闻我说想要孩子
If you ever hear me mention anything about wanting kids,
务必给我来几拳让我清醒
please feel free to punch me in the liver.
此话怎讲
Why?
简直就是魔音灌耳
It's like Satan's alarm clock.
豪斯又在打什么鬼主意
What's House up to?
他还什么都没问我要
He hasn't asked me for anything.
规矩得诡异
He's been incredibly well-behaved.
甚至乖乖看门诊了
He's doing his clinic hours.
这现象还真是让人忧虑
That is a sign of concern.
你明明就和我一样了解他
And you know him as well as I do.
他定会时不时跳出来表明一下自己不是善类
He needs to constantly establish he's the alpha dog.
他要回了他的小鸭子  要回了他的办公室
He's got his team back. He's got his office back.
他已经得到了所有他想要的东西
He's got everything he needs.
你还真相信他会有满足的一天
You really believe that-- he's content?
我不想让他用给我搞破坏的方式自我毁灭
I don't want to let House sabotage himself by sabotaging me,
要实现这个目的  我需要你的指导和信任
and I need your guidance and your trust to do that.
别别别
No, no, no.
卡迪和他一出状况就来找我
Cuddy had a problem with House, she came to me.
需要发泄也来找我
Wanted to vent--me.
你也知道结果是什么了
How did that turn out?
你和豪斯之间有问题的话  好好解决它
You have a problem with House, deal with it,
或者另请高明
or find someone else who can.
之前的事情  我很抱歉
I'm sorry about earlier,
不过我们需要诱发反应
but we needed to provoke a reaction.
真是管用
It worked.
我现在都没办法再直视她的眼睛了
I can barely look her in the eyes anymore.
我会想听我的丈夫实话实说
I'd want my husband to tell me the truth.
当然
Sure.
你会觉得好受些  但是她会是什么感觉
You'll feel better, and she'll feel what--
遭人背叛  伤心欲绝
devastated, betrayed?
心痛不已
Heartbroken.
你真的想如此对待她吗
Do you really want to do that to her?
不想
No.
但我没法这样活着
But I can't live like this.
但她可以
But she can.
准备好了
All set.
我们需要你平躺着  尽量放松
All right, we need you to sit back and try to relax.
看着头顶的灯
Just look at the light.
他们在后面修什么呢
What exactly are they building back there?
我的梦
A dream.
脑电图显示无异常脑部活动
The E.E.G. didn't show any abnormal brain activity.
不是光源性癫痫
He doesn't have photic epilepsy.
我知道  因为他得的是嗜铬细胞瘤
I know, because he has a pheochromocytoma.
你说我是错误的
You said I was wrong.
你的错在于没有先排除癫痫
You were wrong not to rule out epilepsy first.
几个小时就能发现这点
That only takes a couple of hours.
找到让他全身充斥着肾上腺素的肿瘤
Finding a tumor that's flushing adrenaline through his system
得要一整晚
is gonna take all night.
监控他的脑部活动  进行持续尿检
Monitor his brain activity, start a continuous urine test
每两小时抽一次血
and blood draws every two hours.
我不行  我要带孩子
I can't! I have my kids!
威尔森十五分钟后就下班了
Wilson's leaving in, like, 15 minutes!
-奇斯和亚当斯负责检查  -谢谢
- Chase and Adams can do the test. - Thank you.
给你按摩床的钱
For the massage bed.
你和朴克去检查小旅馆
You and Park are checking the motel.
他在那里搞的外遇  去看看周围的环境
He was bumping uglies at for environmental factors.
他找不到保姆
He couldn't find a babysitter.
别看了
Get over it.
你非得把咱俩害死
You're gonna get us killed.
她认为我是跑到她地盘上的妓女
She thinks I'm a prostitute on her turf.
示弱才会把你害死
Showing weakness is what gets you killed.
她怎么会认为你是个妓女
Why would she think you're a prostitute?
跟一个年龄大我一倍的人出现在这破旅馆
I'm in a dump with a guy almost twice my age.
她还能怎么想
What else is she gonna think?
我哪有那么老
How old do you think I am?
谁背叛你了
So who cheated on you?
我们刚认识
We just met.
不觉得现在就敞开心扉
Don't you think it's a little early
谈论过去的感情创伤早了点吗
to be dragging up our baggage in front of each other?
谁说我有过创伤
Who says I have baggage?
我知道豪斯入狱后
I know when House went to prison,
你退出了医生这行
you quit medicine.
-没人会这么做  除非...  -我没退出
- You don't do that unless-- - I didn't quit.
只是休长假
I took a vacation.
我知道等他出来  就能回来工作
I knew when he got out, I'd get my job back.
豪斯自己都没想到要回来
House didn't even know he was coming back.
我相信他
I had faith.
这分明就是受过伤的人才会说的话
Now, that has baggage stamped all over it.
出现癫痫了吗
Seizure activity?
不是  是某个传感器松了
No. One of the sensors came loose.
我去弄好
I'll fix it.
看到什么了
What is it?
不是嗜铬细胞瘤
Not a pheochromocytoma.
病人颈部出现一个肿块
Our patient now has a mass in his neck,
他的体温在过去三小时持续上升
and his body temp's been rising over the last three hours.
装修工人都哪去了
Where is the construction crew?
我可不会让他们没日没夜得干活
Well, I'm not gonna make them work day and night.
就让他们晚上来
So I chose night.
而尿检和血检显示
And his urine and blood tests
没有会造成肾上腺素分泌的肿瘤
didn't show any evidence of an adrenaline-secreting tumor.
脑膜炎  可以做腰椎穿刺来确认
Meningitis. We can do a lumbar puncture to confirm.
抱歉  我得把我的孩子送到
Sorry. I had to drop my kids off
城市另一头的托儿所
at day care across town.
-我错过了什么  -不是脑膜炎
- What'd I miss? - It's not meningitis.
他的脖子没有僵直  精神状态也正常
His neck isn't stiff, and his mental status is normal.
他只是在猜测
He's only guessing.
我在跟陶博说
I'm talking to Taub.
在做亲子测试前  还不能说是"我的孩子"
He can't say "my kids" until he lets me test them.
跟我说说他的情人屋
Tell me about the love shack
他被着老婆搞外遇的地方
where he cheated on his bride.
硬币派上用场了
Quarters came in handy.
我的孩子爱死按摩床了
My kids loved the massage bed.
检测结果显示床上有...
Lab tests show the bed tested positive for,
精液  阴道分泌物
semen, vaginal secretions,
唾液  和排泄物
saliva, and fecal matter,
人和动物的都有
both human and animal.
等你回家了
Probably want to boil the kids
最好给孩子彻底消下毒
for a couple hours when you get home.
浴室里也检测出
The bathroom also tested positive
五种不同的致病菌
for five different types of pathogenic bacteria.
坏死梭杆菌便是其中之一
Fusobacterium necrophorum was one of them.
-是的  你怎么知道  -脖子上的肿块
- Yeah. How'd you know? - The bulge in his neck.
细菌侵入他的咽旁间隙
Bacteria colonized his parapharyngeal space,
移动到颈静脉  形成了血栓
moved into his jugular vein, causing a thrombus--
是雷米尔综合症
Lemierre's syndrome.
用阿莫西林和克拉维酸治疗
Treat with amoxicillin and clavulanic acid.
在血块移动到肺部害死他前
Take out the clot before it moves to his lungs
把它取出来
and kills him.
你身上有无数的细胞
You got at least a trillion cells.
我总归能趁你不备弄到手
You're gonna misplace one of them eventually.
我必须跟我妻子说实话
I have to tell my wife the truth.
手术后你有的是时间说
There's plenty of time for that after the operation.
如果我死了呢
What if I die,
某一天她发现我曾欺骗过她
and one day she finds out I cheated on her?
我就没有机会解释
I'll never be able to explain,
告诉她我有多么抱歉
never tell her how sorry I am.
你在这里每浪费一秒
You're increasing the odds of that
那样的几率就越大
every second we waste here.
不  在跟她谈话前我是不会同意手术的
No, I'm not agreeing to anything until I talk to her.
爸爸
Daddy!
小家伙们
Hey, guys.
你的脖子看着真恐怖
Your neck looks really gross.
我好想你们
I missed you both so much.
但我需要你们帮个忙
But I need to ask you favor.
我要跟妈妈单独说会儿话
I need to talk to Mommy alone for a second.
能帮忙照看一下他们吗
Would you mind watching them for us?
他就是个傻瓜
This guy's an idiot.
我觉得他说的有道理
I think he actually has a good point.
如果多年后  你发现死去的爱妻
What would you think if you found out years later
曾背叛过你  你会怎么想
your beloved dead wife cheated on you?
我不会相信
I wouldn't believe it.
只要不是她亲口对我说的
As long as I don't hear it directly from her,
我至少可以抱有"这不是真的"的希望
then I can hang on to hope that it's not true.
但他这么做...
But this way...
她要么离开他  要么原谅他
she has to either dump him or forgive him.
孩子们  收拾东西  我们走了
Guys, get your stuff. We're leaving.
非常抱歉
I'm so sorry.
我会回来的
I'll be back.
我要把孩子送到我母亲家里
I'm gonna drop our kids off at my mother's.
他犯了个错误
Look, he made a mistake...
一个愚蠢  难以饶恕的错误
A stupid, horrible mistake.
但我们会解决的
But we'll get through this.
现在我只希望我丈夫能好起来
All I care about right now is that my husband gets better.
昨天很抱歉
Sorry about yesterday.
豪斯就是《飞天万能车》里的儿童猎手
House was like the child catcher from Chitty Chitty Bang Bang.
他为何这么关心孩子是不是我的
Why is he so obsessed with my kids being my kids?
因为他看出了不稳定因素
Because he sees insecurity,
当豪斯发现别人软弱时  他就会进攻
and when House senses weakness, he pounces.
而令他感到不安的是
And because his insecurity
其他人拥有的信任
is the fact that other people can have faith
无需他们强迫性地去找寻支持的理由
and don't have the obsessive need for physical proof.
同时  他开了个赌局
Also, he started a betting pool
赌哪个孩子是你亲生的
on which kid is yours and which isn't.
整间医院的人都在赌孩子是不是我的
An entire hospital betting on the legitimacy of my kids?
重新回到朋友之中的感觉真好
It's great to be back among friends.
这事儿错不在我
I'm not the bad guy here.
我赌的可是两个孩子都是你的
I'm betting on them both being yours.
赢了钱我会捐给慈善机构的
I would have donated the money to charity.
接近血栓
Approaching the clot.
正在等待
Stand by for...
这不是血栓
It's not a clot.
这是他的淋巴结
It's his lymph nodes.
肿块不是由化脓或者出血引起的
The bulge wasn't caused by pus or blood.
是组织感染导致的
It's tissue inflammation.
-怎么感染的那么严重  -是淋巴瘤
- How can there be that much tissue  - Lymphoma.
我们要做个活组织检查
We need to take a biopsy.
我没割破什么吧
Did I nick something?
-不知道  -未见出血
- I don't know. - I don't see any bleeding in here.
他的巩膜出现黄疸
His sclera's jaundiced.
我想是肝出问题了  肝衰竭了
I think it's his liver. It's failing.
我们无缘无故就做了个大手术
We did a major operation for no reason.
不是雷米尔氏综合症
It's not Lemierre's Syndrome.
反正我们也要给他的淋巴结做活检的
We would have had to biopsy his lymph nodes anyway
看看是不是癌症
to check for cancer.
活检显示不是癌症
Which it's not. Biopsy was clean.
有可能是酒精戒断的反应
We could be dealing with an alcoholic going through withdrawal.
这可以解释他的心脏问题
It explains his heart,
癫痫和肝衰竭
seizures, and liver failing.
但是解释不通淋巴结肿大
But not his swollen lymph notes.
你为什么要在这里蹭有线电视
Why are we stealing cable from here?
办公室里又没电视
We don't even have a TV in our office.
我是一个
I'm an ex-con
想要从良的惯犯
trying to adjust to a world that's passed me by.
只懂小偷小摸
Stealing's all I know,
同时我对病人的症状推断
that and the fact that I was right
也是正确的
about what's wrong with our patient.
只是对症结还不清楚
Just wrong about what?
豪斯的意思是这不是雷米尔氏症候群
He means it's not Lemierre's,
但确实是感染
but it's still an infection,
这就是为什么扩散得那么快
which is why it's spreading so rapidly.
做切片培养需要时间
Cultures take time,
他的肝脏恐怕坚持不了多久了
and his liver doesn't have much left.
所以我们要给他服用广谱抗生素
That's why we're gonna blast him with broad-spectrum antibiotics.
这样做会毁了他剩余的肝功能
The blast will fry what's left of his liver.
这样治疗会要了他的命
The cure will kill him.
我们先给他肝脏移植
Not if we get him a liver transplant first
再给他用广谱抗生素就行了
and then treat him with a broad spectrum.
老队伍获胜
And old team for the win!
不是我要记分
Not that I'm keeping score.
也就是量化一下大家的表现
It's more of a grid where I assign numerical values
来决定谁能加薪
to determine who gets raises,
谁能休假  谁能获得我的尊重
vacation time, and my respect.
我们将他列上了肝脏移植名单
We have him on the donor list for a liver.
但是这需要时间
But these things take time.
就是说他可能死在移植前
So he could die before he gets one.
有这个可能  但我们还有一个选择
It's a possibility. But we have another option.
我们能从活体捐献者身上
We can do a partial liver transplant
做部分肝脏移植手术
from a living donor.
我来吧
I'll do it.
也要你配型相符才行  但是为了增加几率
If you're a match, but to increase our odds,
我们希望你们的朋友和亲人都能做个检测
we'd like to get your friends and family tested as well.
这手术安全吗
Is it safe?
是个大手术
It's a major surgery.
捐献者一般住院一周
The donor spends a week in the hospital
之后在家修养三个月
and up to three months convalescing at home.
我不能让别人为我冒风险
I can't ask someone to do that for me.
成千上百的人愿意为你这么做
There are hundreds of people who would do that for you.
因为他们不知道我真实的一面
Because they don't know the real me.
你是个好人
You are a good man
只是犯了一个错误
who made a mistake.
那我必须先向他们说明
Then I have to tell them first.
你也要考虑下我的感受
I have to live with this too.
我知道
I know.
我很抱歉  但
And I'm sorry, but...
只有这样我才能让他们帮我
this is the only way that I can do this.
在我请求各位
Before I ask any of you
为我牺牲三个月的生命之前
to sacrifice three months of your life for me,
我要坦白
I have a confession.
我有过外遇
I had an affair.
我做了对不起德尼丝的事
I cheated on Denise.
我不会怪你们  如果你们决定...
I wouldn't blame anyone if you decide...
我原谅他了
I forgive him.
这件事就到此为止吧
That should be enough for all of us.
谢谢你们能来
Thank you so much for coming here...
我话还没说完
There's more.
拉里
Larry.
我给你的卡车新装的变速器
That new transmission I put in your truck,
根本没那个必要
you didn't need it.
乔  你也没必要重装引擎
Joe, same thing with the engine rebuild.
事实上  我欺骗过今晚在场的大多数人
In fact, I cheated most of you here tonight.
有半数的时候  你们送来
Half the time you bring your cars
我维修厂的车子  没有任何问题
into my garage, there's nothing wrong with them.
我敲你们竹杠有些年头了
I've been ripping you all off for years.
我还从嘉实奖学基金里私吞了一万块钱
I also took $10,000 from the Harvest Scholarship Fund,
赌博全输光了
and I lost it gambling.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
我不是你们认为的那个人
I'm not the man you thought I was.
进展真是太顺利了
That went over well.
最后两个没走的捐助者
Out of the two donors who didn't walk out,
他们的配型都不符合
both were negative for a potential match.
坦露真相很可能就这样害死他了
Telling the truth may have just killed this guy.
我让他告诉老婆偷腥的事
I told him to tell his wife he cheated,
没让他把旧账都翻出来
not confess every sin he's ever committed.
如果每个人都像他一样
If everyone did that,
我们永远别想找到捐献者了
we'd never find a donor for anyone again.
不是每个人都会欺骗和讹诈
Everybody doesn't lie, cheat, or steal
-自己的朋友  -他们会的
- from their friends. - Yeah, they do.
可能没这个人那么极品
Maybe not as much as this guy,
但如果人们只说真话
but if people told nothing but the truth,
这世界一定会乱套的
the world would probably burn down overnight.
有些人觉得现在已经乱了
Some people think it's burning now.
如果人们不撒谎的话会好点
Maybe if everybody didn't lie.
这太有爱了
Aw, that is cute.
我在说你的胸部
I'm talking about your breasts.
你每次认真说事的时候胸部总会活灵活现的
They always get perky when you're being painfully earnest.
这是真话
Truth.
听着不舒服对吧
It's uncomfortable, isn't it?
还有一点也是真的
More truth.
我之所以注意到是因为奇斯在盯着看
I only noticed because Chase was staring at them.
他会死不认账  因为他不想冒犯你
He'd never admit it, because he doesn't want to offend you.
正因如此  他也不会告诉你
Same reason he'd never tell you
他想和你上床
that he's thought about having sex with you.
虽然  有一说一  每个遇到你的男人
Although, to be fair, every man you've ever met
都会对你性致盎然
has thought about having sex with you.
他们都会撒谎否认  因为如果你知道了
They'll lie, because if you knew
很可能就不会和他们翻云覆雨了
you probably wouldn't want to have sex with them.
这些只是过去一分钟里的谎话
And that's just some of the lies from the last minute.
接下来有个更大的谎言
And here's a bigger one.
你对我前面说的早就知晓  只是装作不知道
You already know this, but you pretend you don't,
因为那样显得你比较文明
because it makes you feel civilized.
大多数人觉得忽视真相会过得自在些
Most people find it easier to ignore the truth.
问问陶博就知道了
Ask Taub.
我们的病人等不到
Our patient can't wait for a transplant
那个遥遥无期的移植了
that's never gonna come.
该采取极端且鲁莽的办法了
We need to get reckless and extreme.
用CT定位他肝脏坏死的地方并予以切除
C.T. his liver, find the damaged area, and cut it out.
但愿剩下的部分还能够
Hopefully, what's left will be enough
承受广谱抗生素治疗
so we can start treatment with broad-spectrum antibiotics.
十分抱歉第一次让你们俩呆在一起
I'm sorry the first time I had both of you together
我得工作
I had to work.
不过爸爸的老板是个混蛋
But daddy's boss is what we call a jackass.
很好  待在那
Good. Stay right there.
我也为...
I'm also sorry...
我将要做的事感到抱歉...
for what I'm about to do...
因为...
Because...
因为没有什么能改变我对你俩的感情
because nothing will ever change how I feel about you guys.
不过..
But...
不过爸爸很脆弱而且需要知道
but daddy is weak and needs to know.
凌晨12点半  你怎么还在
30 in the morning. Why are you still here?
豪斯还在
House is here
而且明显在为一个
and apparently prepping for an operation
可能导致病人死亡的手术做准备
that will probably kill a patient.
如果有其它解决方法我也不会这么做
I wouldn't be doing this if I thought there was another way.
有啊  他需要肝移植
There is. He needs a transplant.
你手头就有合适的肝吗
You have one lying around?
因为如果未来几小时内没有的话他就会死
'cause he'll be dead if he doesn't get one in the next few hours.
那也是自然原因造成的
That falls under natural causes.
如果他死在你手里我们就会面临...
If you kill him, we're looking at...
死了就是死了
Dead is dead.
我们的律师可不是这么认为的
Not as far as our lawyers are concerned.
我不是要当恶人
I'm not being a dick.
这是个现实问题
This is a real issue,
我得从大局出发
and I have to worry about the big picture now.
我不需要
I don't.
我只是要做你一年前也会做的事
I'll be doing what you would have done a year ago.
我会进行这个手术
I'll be in surgery.
奇斯...
Chase...
你得看看这个
You need to check this out.
这是10小时前他肝脏的CT成像
This is a C.T. scan of his liver from ten hours ago...
这是现在的
This is from now.
肝脏在自我修复
It's healing itself.
我离开时
When I left the room,
他正跟她说单身派对上脱衣舞女郎的事
he was telling her about the strippers from his bachelor party.
肝功能已经改善了百分之三十
Liver function has improved 30%--
在他必须进行肝移植前我们又赢得了几天时间
Buys us a few extra days before he'll need a transplant.
有趣的是  它为什么会自我修复呢
Interesting question is, why is it regenerating?
还有这场景
And scene.
现在回到无聊的现实中
Now we're back to boring reality reality.
他之前有过肝昏迷
His liver was in shock before.
他住院以来一直有过敏反应
He's been having an allergic reaction since he got here.
这可以解释为什么他的症状发展如此迅速
Could explain why his symptoms appeared so rapidly.
也可能是症状消失的原因
And maybe starting to go away.
我们得进行划痕实验查找诱因
We need to run a scratch test to find out what set it off.
或者是谁  一切都起源于他对妻子不忠
Or who. This all started when he cheated on his wife.
他对某人过敏吗
He's allergic to a person?
或是她的
Or something she's wearing--
化妆品或是香水
makeup, perfume,
避孕用品  凯蒂猫玩偶
birth control method, her "Hello kitty" doll.
你们去找那女人和诱因
Two of you go find her and find out what.
你们俩在进行划痕实验的同时
Two of you start treatment with corticosteroids
使用糖皮质激素和肾上腺素进行治疗
and epinephrine while you run the scratch test.
你们认为是我引起的吗
You think I did this to him?
也许是你穿的用的或是给他的东西
Or something you wear, own, use, or gave him.
我就给了他个避孕套  他没带
I gave him a condom. He didn't have one.
-哪种  -我不知道是哪种
- What kind? - I don't know what kind.
我在健康日活动工作时拿的
I got it from the health fair I was working at.
-你在医疗机构工作吗  -我是形象大使
- You're in the medical profession? - I'm Miss Cedarville.
健康日活动是我的职责之一
The health fair is one of my responsibilities.
另一职责是和38岁已婚男子乱搞吗
Is another one hooking up with 38-year-old married men?
我猜我该充当白脸
I guess I'm supposed to be the good cop.
我知道这很难
I know this is tough.
不过你记住的任何事都可能挽救他的生命
But anything you can remember might help save his life.
他送我回家  然后...
He was giving me a ride home, and...
他看上去总是很友善
he always seemed so nice.
然后我们就去了汽车旅馆
And then we ended up at the motel.
现在人人都在议论这事
And now everybody's talking about it.
如果他们发现那是我
And if they find out it was me,
我就会丢掉我的头衔甚至工作
I'm gonna lose my title and probably my job.
城里的人都不会再跟我说话了
And no one in town is ever gonna speak to me again.
我犯了个错误  现在这错误会毁了我的生活
I made a mistake, and now it's gonna end up ruining my life.
德尼丝再也不会想见到我了
Denise never wants to see me again.
你还以为会发生什么
What did you think was gonna happen?
我厌倦了生活在谎言之中
I was sick of living a lie.
每个人都爱我  每个人都指望着我
Everybody loved me. Everybody looked up to me.
但是...
But...
我不配
I didn't deserve it.
谁都会犯错
Everybody makes mistakes.
只是通常他们不会同时将所有错误都公之于众
They just don't usually broadcast all of them at the same time.
如果我都要死了
Well, if I'm gonna die,
我宁愿干净的离去
I might as well do it with a clean soul.
如果你活下来呢
And if you live?
你还没过河呢
You didn't just burn bridges.
就先把桥给拆了
You torched, nuked, and salted the earth with them.
人人都要为所犯的罪过付出代价
Everybody has to pay for their sins.
感觉就像你在用烧火棍捅我
Oh, it feels like you stuck me with a hot poker.
过敏反应
An allergic reaction.
是来自小麦过敏源
It's the swab for wheat-based allergies.
我一辈子都在吃小麦
I've been eating wheat my entire life.
我不对小麦过敏
I'm not allergic to wheat.
现在感觉全身像着火了一样
Now it feels like my whole body's on fire.
这没道理啊
This doesn't make any sense.
当我用含小麦过敏源的试纸测试时
He broke out with a rash
他皮肤上起了很多皮疹
right after I tested with the wheat-allergy swab,
但没有任何一项血液指标证明他对此过敏
But none of his blood samples show he's allergic to it.
那就不是过敏
Then he's not allergic to it.
也许是糖皮质激素起了什么作用
Could the corticosteroids have somehow caused it?
他发皮疹时我还没给他注射糖皮质激素
I didn't hook them up yet. After he broke out,
我想在对他用药前先确定是否为谷类过敏源
I wanted to confirm it was gluten before we dosed him.
也可能是乳胶过敏  起初由避孕套引起
Could be a latex allergy. Started with a condom,
然后我们戴的手套用的仪器造成了持续性刺激
and we kept it going with our gloves and equipment.
在乳胶试验中他也没表现出阳性反应
He doesn't test positive for that either.
他的血样在任何试验中都没表现出阳性反应
None of his samples test positive for anything.
那他就是对某些没测试过的东西过敏
Then he's allergic to something not on the tests.
我继续查
I'll keep looking here.
我们开始用类固醇治疗看是否能将过敏源清除
We'll start the steroids and see if it clears up.
你只有一个病人却有三份DNA结果
You have one patient and three DNA results?
否则我怎么比较家族性遗传病
How else do I compare them to other genetic disorders?
怎么回事
What's up?
奇斯基本上把我归为叛徒了
Chase basically called me a sellout.
就因为你把白大褂挂起来以谋求更多的薪水
Just because you hung up your lab coat for more money
和更大的办公室吗
and a bigger office?
我将其束之高阁是因为卡迪走后得有人负责
I hung it up because someone had to run this place after Cuddy left.
外面有的是管理人才
There are a lot of good administrators out there,
好医生却没几个
not many good doctors.
比你想的多多了
More to it than you think.
比如说
For example,
你正在看的是猴子的DNA
you're looking at monkey dna.
我的分析是
My analysis--
豪斯在操纵你进行DNA测试后偷去了测试结果
House took your results after he manipulated you into providing them.
他就像蛇一样在蜕皮
He's shedding his skin like a snake.
如果是过敏反应
If it was an allergic reaction,
那么糖皮质激素和肾上腺激素治疗
the corticosteroids and epinephrine
只会使他好转而不会恶化
would have made him better, not worse.
有人在思考答案吗
Is everyone trying to think of an answer?
还是每个人都不敢说出所想的答案
Or is everyone afraid to say what they think the answer is?
我就当你们是后者了
I take it you're in the latter category.
史蒂文斯—约翰逊综合征
Stevens-Johnson Syndrome...
符合所有症状  并且可以解释
it fits all of his symptoms and explains
为何用过类固醇之后他的病情恶化
why he got worse after the steroids.
几乎所有药物治疗都会使该病加剧
Most medication exacerbates the condition.
不治之症
There's no treatment for it.
符合
It fits.
病例到此结束
Case closed.
你们何不回家睡会儿觉
Why don't you go home and get some sleep?
我感觉像在地狱一样
I feel like I'm in hell.
不能给你使用过多的止痛药物
We can't give you too much pain medication,
不然你的病情会更糟
or we'll make your condition worse.
我还有最后一件事要忏悔
I got one final confession to make.
还有什么
What's left...
你逃税了吗
You cheated on your taxes?
我杀过人
I'm a murderer.
我杀了我的合伙人
I killed my business partner.
一枪打在他头上
I shot him in the head.
然后伪造自杀现场
I made it look like suicide.
而且他只是第一个
And he was just the first.
你还杀了其他人
You killed more?
还有三个
Three...
或者四个
or four.
我回来之前别再杀人
Try not to kill anyone else until I get back.
是神经病变  他的大脑前交通动脉
It's neurological. There's an aneurysm
有一个动脉瘤
in the anterior communicating artery of his brain...
正是负责冲动控制与抑制的部位
the area moderating impulse control and compulsion.
神经瘤越长越大
As it grew larger,
他承认的事也越来越离谱
so did the confessions.
看着
Watch.
鲍勃  我储物柜里丢了一只鞋
Bob, one of my shoes is missing from my locker.
对不起
I'm so sorry.
我正需要钱
I-I needed the cash, and, um,
你的柜子正开着
the locker was open.
我从未听说有神经疾病
I never heard of a neurological problem
会导致皮肤脱落
that causes someone's skin to fall off.
因为根本没有这样的病
Because there isn't one.
动脉瘤只是另一个症状
The aneurysm is just another symptom.
而不是病因
It's not the cause.
把这些都考虑进去  不难想到
You add them all together, we get...
不难想到川...
We get Kaw... Kawas... Kawas...
川崎病
It's Kawasaki's Disease.
那是自身免疫疾病
It's autoimmune.
没错  我们都知道"川崎"什么意思
Yes, we knew what "Kawah" meant.
我们只是想  川崎病通常只在
We just figured since it basically presents
亚洲儿童身上出现
only in Asian children...
也不是说没有可能患病
Which you might have, by the way.
所以我们才会将它遗漏
Which is basically why we missed it.
地毯依然...
Rug burns...
研究显示某些地毯清洁剂
certain carpet-cleaning chemicals
与川崎病有关
have been linked to it.
开始静脉注射免疫球蛋白治疗
Start treatment with intravenous immunoglobulin.
看着动脉瘤
Monitor the aneurysm.
若它不自行消退  就得我们动手了
If it doesn't resolve itself, we'll have to repair it.
你们其他人
The rest of you...
思路不够开阔
Aren't surfing enough.
猴子DNA  好想法
Monkey DNA... nice touch.
真的吗
Really?
你不认为我应该用老鼠DNA吗
You don't think I should have gone with rat?
我还自我怀疑了一整天呢
I've been second-guessing myself all day.
检测结果在哪里
Where are the DNA results?
先承认我是对的
First admit that I was right.
是你使手段让我去测的
You manipulated me into doing it.
好  我承认
Yeah, I'll admit to that.
你也得承认  鼓动你相当容易
Now you admit that it was incredibly easy,
因为心诚则无人可欺
because you can't cheat an honest man.
我爱她们
I love them.
就算其中有一个不是我亲生  我也不在乎
I don't care if one of them isn't biologically mine.
如果两个都不是呢
What about both?
有可能哦  我还没看
Could be. Haven't read these.
现在承认我是对的吧
Now say I was right.
不  我承认我一时软弱
No. I'll admit I was weak for a moment,
但我不要看结果
but I'm not doing this.
我不在乎
I don't care.
你在乎  我能证明
You do, and I'll prove it.
你希望我把结果扔进碎纸机
I will shred this.
撤掉赌局  归还赌金
I will call off my pool, return the money,
此事一笔勾销
and we'll forget all about it.
还是我们去实验室灯箱前
Or we'll go to the light box in the lab
一睹真相
and know the truth once and for all.
停
Stop.
让我看看
Let me see them.
只是想确定一下全部结果都在里面
Just wanted to make sure all three were inside.
镇长查过了
The mayor checked.
奖学基金并没有资金被挪用
There wasn't any money missing from the scholarship fund.
奇斯医生跟我说了
Dr. Chase told me...
你的病
about your disease,
你不由自主承认一些没做过的错事
how it made you confess to crimes you hadn't committed.
你跟别人有外遇的事
The affair with that girl...
是真的吗
is that real?
亲爱的  我...
Honey, I...
永远都不会
would never...
也从来没做过对不起你的事
have never cheated on you.
我就知道你不会那样对我
I knew you could never do that to me.
不知怎么的
I don't know how...
可我就是知道
but I knew.
看来你休息一年并没荒废了医术  我很高兴
Glad to see taking a year off didn't dull your skill set.
走运而已
I got lucky.
那天晚上的事...
About the other night...
这份工作的麻烦已经够多了
I have enough problems with this job.
我想我不应该再自寻烦恼
Second-guessing my best doctors
去怀疑我最优秀的医生们
shouldn't be one of them.
怎么到这儿来了
Why are you up here?
你现在有自己的办公室和洗手间了
You have your own bathroom and office now.
我来冲澡  已经四天没离开医院了
Shower. I haven't left the hospital in four days.
为什么
Why?
豪斯一直不回家
House won't go home.
我不能让他脱离我的监管留在医院
And there's no way I'm leaving him here unsupervised.
豪斯什么都不做
House is screwing with you...
是在故意整你
by not screwing with you.
他整晚都在看电视喝马提尼
He's watching TV and drinking martinis all night.
还能让你为了找出并不存在的计划
Meanwhile, he's keeping you here searching for a plan
急得团团转
that doesn't even exist.
我怎么没看出来呢
How the hell did I not see that?
你回来我很高兴
I'm glad you're back.
我也很高兴
Me too.
浴缸还是桑拿
Either a hot tub or a sauna.
浴缸就好
A hot tub would be cool.
新旧组员们大家好
New team, old team...
仅向诸位呈现
I present...
新版外间办公室一期成果
phase one of operation outer office 2.0.
毫无变化
Nothing's changed.
一切都变了
Oh, everything has changed.
不
No.